Thank you.
who he was, that he was like a little bit for his ultimate resurrection.
And so this is a really great series for those who are spiritually curious and are wondering
what does the Bible say about Jesus?
Who is this guy that has literally kind of messed up the entire world?
Like, it's changed everything since he came.
And if you're considering that, this is a great series.
If you have been following Jesus for a long time, it's also a great series because we tend
to drift, we tend to kind of grab ideas around Jesus that are preached to us without ever
really looking at the text and remember if the text says that's who Jesus is.
So sometimes, myself included, I literally get paid to study the text and sometimes I end
up walking away with ideas that I think are true about Jesus and I'm not so true about
Jesus because I didn't look to the Bible.
So, great series of studies about it.
Let me pray and remember what happened to us first by name.
Father, thank you so much for this opportunity to examine your word.
I pray that your Holy Spirit would be present in the throne of Jesus, teaching us the word.
And may I just be in the end of the best word that you pray for the glory of my God.
In the name of God, amen.
So if you want to follow along, we're going to be in John chapter 2.
John chapter 2, starting in verse 1.
I'm going to need some crowd participation today.
How many of you are fans of who don't murder mystery?
You know, it's becoming a more popular example.
We've got some people that Melissa has recruited me into this team.
I was never a who don't murder mystery type person.
But she was reading like everything at this a cliche of a rip, right?
And so now I've lost all of the hercule, hercule, hercule, I can't say it.
That's the hard thing to say on stage in front of people.
So I've become a fan of this genre, and it really is a fun genre because there's kind of this fun narrative that you get to follow along with all throughout the book or the video.
In my case, it's not a book.
It is a TV series or a movie.
She hasn't recruited me that much yet.
I haven't read the first book yet.
But I mean, it is great, and you're kind of trying to follow along.
You're looking for clues to kind of figure out what's going on.
But oftentimes, almost always in my case, what happens is you get to the end of the movie, and the detective tells you who did it.
And you're like, I'm just not going to talk to this.
How did you know that?
And then the detective walks back, and you kind of re-watch the story, and the detective draws out some ideas or some clues that he picked up on or she picked up on throughout the story.
And so as I studied this first Song, this first miracle of Jesus in the Gospel of John, I really felt like I was seeing what happened in the text.
That John leads out this narrative, this miracle that Jesus does, and it's a pretty cool miracle.
Like, just on the surface level, you just read it.
Especially, like, those of you that like wine, you're like, I didn't get down with this Jesus guy, right?
I didn't sit in the water and the wine.
This is cool.
I like him.
And so it's a cool miracle.
It's a cool story.
But then, the more you examine the text, the deeper you look at it, there is some low-level layers of symbolism that I see John is kind of like a detective in a murder mystery.
He's giving you the story, and if that's all you get, it's great.
But he's also giving you clues for you to see a story underneath the story.
There's deep symbolism underneath the success.
This is the most exciting, I'm going to be honest with you, this is the most exciting I've been about a sermon in a long time.
So, you guys know I'm not an emotional preacher.
If I start to get pumped a little bit, a little bit of feedback might have heard in you by the way.
So, we see how I guess there's, there's this deep symbolism in the text, and we see this throughout the Gospels.
The Gospel writings will say, like, this happened, and this is how we understood it.
And then, after the resurrection, we were like, oh, it makes so much more than the thing that we thought it made when it happened.
And so, I think what John's doing here is he's sharing the story pre-resurrection, but then, obviously, he's writing it post-resurrection.
So, he's dropping some hints and images.
These are some things that we didn't know in the moment, but now, looking back, we totally get it.
Does that make sense?
So, what I'd like to do is the first, like, short section, and just kind of walk through the details of the narrative on its surface level.
Draw out a little bit of apatism, but then I want to come back to the symbolism towards reading.
Is that some of the good points?
All right.
So, John chapter 2, we'll read this from 5 verses.
John says,
On the third day, there was a wedding at Canaan and Galilee, and the mother of Jesus was there.
I'll be married.
Jesus also was invited to the wedding with his disciples.
He didn't have all 12.
He had four at this point.
When the wine rang out, the mother of Jesus said to him,
They have no wine.
That's fine.
There's no wine.
And Jesus said to her,
Woman, what does this have to do with me and all the moms?
And he really said, I thought I'd use this for his family.
Right?
We'll get to that.
He says,
My hour has not yet come.
His mother said to the servants,
Do whatever he tells you.
So, a little bit of context here.
First, John is a literary master.
He's always doing, like, he's giving you little funds for all the justice.
If I don't have someone who's smarter than me, someone who's giving you a clue, I wouldn't know it.
Okay?
But this one's pretty obvious.
On the third day, John is starting the first time with a phrase that's going to connect it to the last time.
Right?
The resurrection of Jesus, God, and on the third day.
So, John's just getting, like, a little clue, like, hey.
This is the first miracle, and it's all building towards something that's all of them.
So, on the third day, there was a wedding at Tina in Galilee.
So, we didn't even know about Jewish wedding ceremonies, because there were multiple days.
Long ceremonies.
Couples would be engaged.
The green words go back.
If you prepare for the life after the ceremony, you would also prepare for the ceremony.
And then all of their guests and family would come in.
And so, it's important that this is a well-planned-out process, because you've got people coming in and going with you.
So, it's a hospitality culture.
You're dependent on the hospitality values.
There's no hotels, right?
Like, you've got to stay with people.
And so, people are coming from out of town for this wedding, and Mary comes to Jesus, and she says,
You've got a problem.
There's no running, right?
There's running out.
And all the ladies in the room said, Yeah, this is why we don't want people planning the weddings in the night.
Right?
So, I want to make sure we get the importance of this statement.
This is a massive bad thing to happen.
Like, you'd be bad if it happened in the wedding today.
But this is, like, horribly bad.
Because not only is it a hospitality culture, these people are expecting the greens to provide food and wine for them.
Like, they made this trip.
And they made their plans based on, There's going to be provisions for me at this wedding.
There's actually one commentator I heard say that he came across documents that he didn't reference them.
I think he said it from Steve.
So, let me take his word for it.
So, there were actually lawsuits that would happen at this time.
Because there was a contractual agreement.
And we're making this trip.
And you're going to say, Make sure that we don't buy while we're in your place.
Right?
And so, that culture is really important to have enough food and enough wine for everyone at the wedding.
And it's an honor same culture.
Right?
And so, the groom and the bride are, like, meaning, like, if we let people go, if we make this huge mistake for us,
And it was the groom's responsibility to provide the woman.
Mary knows her system, knows where he's thinkable of, even though he hasn't yet done anything.
She quotes her family for help.
Maybe she quotes him because he's all of a sudden, and she's like,
Hey, can you, like, grab a cane more, and I'll go somewhere and get some wine.
Or, what I probably think happens, is Mary is a woman of great faith who also understands the pictures there was.
She sings a song of rejoicing in Luke, and it's filled with allusions from the Old Testament.
This woman knew the Scriptures.
She had faith in who the Messiah was to be seen, and her son was the Messiah to come.
So, Mary is a woman of great faith who knows the Old Testament well.
In Amos, at the end of Amos, there is a clear prophecy that when Messiah comes, the rain will be filled with wine.
So, I think Mary's like, okay.
It's kind of like a ring ring to me.
She's probably somehow relationally connected to the rain or the bride, and she's like,
This is a bad thing for the people that I love.
Also, my son's a Messiah, and my younger Messiah comes, wine is plenty.
When you're in the situation here, anybody, right?
So, she comes to Jesus, and she's like, Okay, I've got an idea.
I'm going to give us a one, I think.
And Jesus responds, Woman, what does this have to do with me?
My hour has not yet come.
A lot of things are going on in this conversation.
I'll do my best to stand by this.
First of all, woman is not as rude as it sounds in this episode.
It is a very clear distinction.
It's a break from love, right?
It's like, you know, he's like breaking this distinction between obsessing her as mother or her as another adult woman in the room.
So, he is breaking, he is making a transition here, which we'll talk about in a little bit.
He says, What does this have to do with you?
Why would he say that?
Because it's the groom's responsibility to provide the one.
It's the groom's legal obligation to provide the one.
And he has not done so.
And so, he said, It's not, this is not my problem.
This is the groom's problem.
He's going to have to figure out the situation.
And secondly, he says, My hour has not yet come.
All throughout the gospel, we're going to see that this hour is ultimately referring to his crucifixion.
But, what we know is the moment that he does a miracle, the moment that he performs a public sign,
he is officially starting his public campaign as a sign.
He says, He's officially starting the things that are going to ultimately proclaim to the nation of Israel,
that I am the promise of the son.
And so, Jesus said, The moment I do this, the cross starts ticking backwards.
Because he knows that his campaign as a sign is going to lead to crucifixion.
The moment he does this, his hour begins.
The time starts ticking.
So, there's a bunch of different theories about all that's going on in this conversation.
But, I don't know if I'm going to look at something, so you're going to hear my favorite theory.
Just know that it's one of a few options.
I think Mary seems to believe that this is a perfect start to use this public ministry.
She comes to him and says,
She says, Wedding is a perfect backdrop for you to do your first miracle.
And she asks him for this to happen.
I don't think she's wrong.
Weddings and wine become major illustrations of Jesus about the kingdom of God.
Now, this really is a perfect backdrop for this first public son.
Jesus pushes back for a couple of reasons.
First, it's the groom's responsibility.
Now, Jesus' responsibility is not anyone else's responsibility.
It's the groom's legal obligation to provide for his gifts.
Again, Jesus wants Mary to understand that if he does this, it's our self-sickening towards crucifixion.
And, I believe he makes this distinct change between mom and woman because what he's telling her is,
The moment I do this, our relationship changes.
You've got to be willing to submit to me as Messiah if this happens.
Like, our relationship is shifting from mother, son, to Messiah, disciple.
This is a big decision.
And he's, I think, having this conversation, everyone around is called a foolish.
Because Jesus hasn't done a miracle yet.
And I really think Jesus and Mary are like, they know what's going on here.
Jesus is saying, are you sure?
And so, he says, things are going to change.
And I think Mary seems to understand the implications of what's happening.
And in space, he responds, do whatever he says.
Oftentimes, space activates Jesus' miracles throughout the gospel.
It's very possible that Mary's faith is activating this miracle to what Jesus is about to form.
So, do whatever he tells you.
Verse 6.
Now, there are six stone water jars.
The Jews write to the feast, and he's holding 20 to 30 gallons.
Jesus said to the servants, fill the jars with water.
And they filled them up to the wind.
He said to him, now draw them up and take it to the master of the feast.
So, they took it.
When the master of the feast tasted the water, now it became watering.
He did not know where it came from, though the servants, who had drawn the water, knew.
The master of the feast called the bread of the rain and said to him, everyone serves the good wine first.
And then people have done freely the poor wine.
But you have kept the good wine until now.
John says, this is the first of the signs.
You must get it to him in glory.
And it manifested his glory.
And his disciples believed in him.
And the last sentence, he said, God must practice his faith.
To proclaim who Jesus is so that we might believe in Jesus.
Let's break down the rest of this.
Classes 6, stone doors for Jewish purification.
Ever since Adam and Eve's beautiful, God in the garden, there's been a relational discourse between God and him.
God reestablishes his relationship with humanity through a covenant with the nation of Israel.
All of these contexts will be covered in the great times of his class on the Bible GPS.
So, if you need more context, that would be a great place to go get it.
So, the nation of the covenant with the nation of Israel, he gives them laws.
And he gives them sacrifices and purification rituals for when they'll break the laws or when they inadvertently become unclean.
Sometimes you become unclean for sins.
Sometimes you become unclean for sins that you can't control.
If you want to know about that, I'll find it.
You want to go to this list?
So, these jars were a part of this system.
When a Jewish person found themselves ceremonially unclean, they would be unable to enter the temple, unable to worship God.
And they would watch themselves from the water and become clean again or become able to worship Jesus.
They're reconciling themselves back to God through this religious ritual.
And I know what you might be thinking.
Is the founder of the largest religion in the world about to take a religious symbol and use it to extend the temple?
Am I the only one that's thinking?
All right.
So, time is we're not really, all right?
Um, yeah.
All right.
So, these, let's say, draw some and take it to the master's ceremony.
This is a real quick side note.
So, Boston, I'm going to do it fast because I don't have time.
I love the fact that he's the first miracle.
The participants, the ones who see everything behind the scenes are the pretty ones.
What a beautiful picture of what throughout Jesus' ministry is going to be very evident about his kingdom, that his kingdom is for those that the power structures look over and take advantage of.
So, Jesus' kingdom is for those who are vulnerable, outcasts, and marginalized.
If this does not fit your view of Jesus, I would ask you to look again.
So, Jesus says to the servants, draw some water and take it to the master's ceremony.
And, um, if you're a servant here, you're in the real pickles.
Because right on the line is like a bad thing.
You're probably going to get some, some shrapnel from all the people that are married because you're the one in it.
Like, you're going to see people be mean to the servant and be like, we don't have the answers for all over, right?
A bunch of hungry Jews with no wine and we'll be like, where is the wine, right?
And also, the alternative is they take this cup of water to the master's families and pretend like it's one.
So, we're going to get some shrapnel there, too, right?
So, we're kind of in this test-play situation, like, do we go tell them if there's no wine or do we listen to this guy and give him water and, like, hope for the best?
So, we're in this real weird situation and they decide, well, you know, I guess water's better than nothing.
Or maybe they saw through Mary's confidence, like, hey, maybe this guy's got some stuff going on.
Worst case scenario, it's better than giving him nothing.
So, if they take the water and it's somewhere between the drawing of the water and the pouring out into the master's glass, it becomes final.
Incredibly radical.
Many implications.
The master of the ceremony says that this is the good wine.
This is the guy that would know, right?
Because it's his job.
His job is to know wines.
This is not blue salt.
This is the National Valley stuff.
And this isn't one glass, but seemingly 120 to 180 gallons of the finest of wine.
So, I know there's none of you in the room, but if we have wine from the stores in the room, what does it take for good wine to be produced?
Time.
It takes time.
Jesus here is demonstrating that he has power and authority both over nature, and in his time he's taking water and he's turning it into wine, and not just wine, but good wine.
Now, he's demonstrating his power over authority, and the authority over nature and time.
I also read an article from a professor who has his doctorate, and he said that there would actually have to be new atoms formed in order to create this wine.
He says he has authority over nature and time, and he's demonstrating his ability to create out of nothing.
This is John's sign in John chapter 1.
In the beginning is the word, the word was God, the word was God.
Everything that was made was made through him.
Jesus is not just a man who does great miracles and signs.
He is God.
What's the result?
His glory is revealed, and the disciples believe.
This sign demonstrates to the disciples, starts to demonstrate to the disciples who Jesus is and what he's capable of.
I remember last week, I gave you an illustration of faith, and for me, the faith to give him an airplane of my brother-in-law's brothers that I had never met before.
My faith was at like 50.001%.
I got an airplane, but I think that's what we see throughout the Gospels, is the disciples have just enough faith to keep following Jesus.
And then you see another miracle, another miracle, and the faith continues to grow.
So if you're in here, and you're like, you're spiritually curious, and you're on like the 49.99% dinner, all the way to zero, and you're like, I'm really not sure about this Jesus God.
And I hope this series moves you from whatever percentage you are, 10, 40, 30, to like 50.001%.
And I believe that as you begin this journey of following Jesus, that your faith will increase the more and more that you seek to know him and follow him.
But for those of us that have been following Jesus, all over that 50.001% I hope that this continually encourages you to grow more and more and more, and I'll say it's stronger and stronger and stronger.
Now, on the surface, this is an incredible miracle.
And in awesome ways that you must have started this public ministry, it has a ton of implications that can encourage us to trust Jesus just like those disciples do.
However, I think John Davis concludes, he, on the other side of the resurrection, he realized the symbolism that was massed before running out.
And this, this is what I'm saying to say a little bit, right?
These are the things in Scripture that give you more and more confidence that Jesus is to recidivism.
It's actually, it's the things that made C.S. Lewis to follow Jesus.
C.S. Lewis was created by all religious facts, of all myths and religious myths.
And it was by studying the Scriptures where he saw the level of detail and symbolism and connection from Adam and Eve all the way to Jesus and beyond.
It was that that gave him the confidence to believe.
And it's why I read things like this and see deep symbolism in Scripture.
I'm like, there's no way that this was accidently happened.
There's no way that we got these 66 books with this much symmetry all pointing to Jesus as a Messiah.
It's not possible.
So, let's look at the implications of what we're going to get post-resurrection and increasing your faith in Jesus,
which I believe will result in both eternal life and the future, an abundant life now.
So, I said I need to cry for this facing.
Quick question, because I'm how brave you are.
Running represents two main things in the Bible.
Anybody know?
Celebration, that was the hard one, so the easier was not.
Blood, right?
So, in the Scriptures, wine represents both blessing and blood.
If we go back in the text and look very carefully,
before you find your message, give me a second,
you just turn into water and the wine twice in this passage.
Let's look at it.
All right.
Verse 8.
So, the servants fill these spirits and stir his eyes up with water.
They fill it to the ground.
And he said to them,
Now, draw some out.
What is some?
Water.
Draw some water out.
Take it to the master's feet.
So, they took it.
What did they take?
Water.
When the master's feet tasted it,
the water had now become one.
And you did not know where it came from,
though the servants who had drawn,
what did they draw?
The water knew where it came from.
So, unless Jesus only turned one glass of water into wine,
and the six stone jars were just for sale,
and he was just rubbing it in the green space,
and he could turn the water into wine,
but he was only going to do a glass,
there's probably now wine in the purification stones as well, right?
It was kind of assumed in the text.
All right, so,
I think that Jesus turned water into wine twice,
once in the purification stones,
and once in the glass of the minister's family.
And I believe that both of these water turned to wine
are meant to represent the two things that wine represents all for us.
Wine's blood in the purification stones,
and wine's blessing and celebration in the glass of the minister's family.
That's unpacked it.
Wine is growing.
Since the Garden of Eden,
God told Adam and Eve that if they chose not to trust him,
the penalty for that decision would be death,
both spiritual and physical.
There's this deep connect between us and God
because we choose not to trust him.
We want to be in control of our own lives.
We want to be in the driver's seat.
I was at a store yesterday,
and the great plastic sign to take the wheel to me, right?
Beautiful.
Anyway, that was decided.
Now, I don't even notice at all.
We want to take the wheel.
We want to be in charge of our life.
And when we make those decisions,
those decisions lead to both spiritual death
and ultimately, though,
the consequence of Adam's first decision,
physical death.
God made our covenant reign of Israel,
and if they obeyed his commands,
he would bless them.
If they disobeyed,
they would have so many lots of abundance
that would be taken into captivity
with all the rest of them happening.
And Israel's system is baked in this
payment for sin
through the blood of innocent enemies.
And so God makes for that agreement with Israel,
and they continually disobey him,
and they offer bad sacrifices.
They don't offer sacrifices at all.
They start losing all the idols.
All of this stuff goes downhill.
Israel has a pattern of failure,
and I would say this,
that Israel has become like a groom
to ring out of wine,
going to live up to their agreement with faith.
See what's happening here?
He's just saying,
it's not my business.
It's the groom's responsibility
to provide the law.
And he's standing steady.
It's Israel's responsibility
to live up to their end of the covenant
in the heaven.
They've failed over and over and over again.
Israel has become like a groom
without any wine,
failing to live up to its responsibility
to the covenant it made this time.
The New Testament essentially says
that the same thing is true
about you and I and you're outside
as a nation of Israel.
Romans chapter 3 says,
for all I'm sinned,
for short of the glory of God.
He's broken this covenant
between us and God.
There's a disconnect
in relationship between us and God.
You and I are like a groom
without wine.
We have failed to live up
to all agreement with God.
to the standards of loving God
physically and loving
a neighbor of themselves.
And the penalty for that failure
is both spiritual
and physical death.
And this story,
which is the shadow
of the ultimate story
of the Bible,
Jesus steps in
to provide for the groom
what he was supposed
to provide.
This is a picture
of what Jesus ultimately
came to do.
He came to provide
a once and for all sacrifice
for us
and our place
for our sins.
Just as Jesus provided
the wine that the groom
was responsible
to provide,
his blood will become
the perfect eternal sacrifice
that will provide
the sins,
a time that we were
supposed to live up to.
It was our death
that he died
on the first.
It's no accident
he used the studies
of purification.
The old
external prison,
temporary
external prison
is going to become
internal
prison.
He's taking
the old covenant
and he's fulfilling it.
He's not abolishing it.
He's fulfilling it.
Luke chapter 42
verse 20 says,
this is the cup
of the new covenant
in my blood.
Jesus
from water
and stones
that I was
into wanting
to represent
his blood
that would ultimately
be the same
that I received
the new covenant.
Christ's sacrifice
fulfilled the requirements
of the Old Testament law.
There would be
no more need
for reputable sacrifices
or eternal cleansings
of the water.
We can now become
entirely clean
from faith
in Jesus.
Come on, people!
Is this good or worse?
Romans 8, 3-4,
the law of Moses
was unable
to save us
because of the weakness
of our sinful nature.
So God did
what the law
could not do.
He sent his own son
in a body
like the bodies
we sinners have
and in that body
God declared
an end
of the sins
control over us
by giving his sons
to sacrifice
for our sins
who did that
so that the just
requirements
our obligation
to the law
would be fully satisfied
for us
who no longer
follow our sinful nature
but instead
follow the Spirit.
I don't know about you
but I am sick
and tired
of the unnecessary
control that I give
than the power
of the law
I'm exhausted
from missing the mark
no matter how hard
I saw it
in my flesh
I cannot seem
to be a better father
or a better husband
or a better pastor
or a better person.
I regularly
and intentionally
choose the selfish way
for myself.
I am like a green
with no one.
I have failed
to live up
to those perfect standards
and I fail
and fail
and fail over again.
And if you want
to keep me
thank you
I am here to tell you
where we
we all get trapped
in this cycle
as past failures
same over our past failures
same over our current addiction
the same power
that turns water
into wine
and that raised Jesus
from the dead
can set you free
from the power
of sin
and shame
in your life
and transform your heart
from the inside of us.
It can restore
broken relationships
it can set you free
from addictions
it can give you peace
in the middle
of difficult circumstances
ultimately
it can give you
abundant life
and eternal life
in the future.
We simply need
to release
control
of Jesus.
We use
to acknowledge
that we have
no wine
and that he has
provided the wine
for us.
Okay
not only is wine
a symbol of blood
in the Scriptures
but it also is
a symbol
of blessing.
Not only does the water
become wine
in the stones
but purification
also becomes
wine in the glass
of the master
of ceremonies.
This wine
represents the blessing
abundance
and celebration
that will come
of the culmination
of Christ's
new covenant.
The second coming
of Christ
becomes his
sacrificial
becomes
his second coming
is because
of his sacrifice
of the exceeded
power of shame
death
and the grave
and is the ultimate
act of sacrificial love.
A day will come
when sin, guilt,
sickness, sadness,
corn, and justice
will be replaced
with abundance
and celebration.
In German records
this sermon
so that you will
trust in Jesus
both as his
sufferings
for even
aliens that come
from the king
and through him
we can walk
an abundant life
now and eternal
life in the future.
That's similar
as this entire
sign with this
one statement
Jesus drank
our cup of suffering
so that we can
drink his cup of
suffering.
No accident
that the water
was from the wine
Jewish purification
stones
it's no accident
but the backstack
for this miracle
is a Jewish
wedding.
Remember I say
at the beginning
of a Jewish wedding
the husband
and the wife
will be declared
and then the husband
will leave
prepared
all of the things
that he needs
to prepare
and then come back
and get to go.
So I'm not saying
to you guys
you've heard of before.
For those of you
that are like
and I get this
I get this
down
to say
but Jesus
really is God
why don't you
just like
stay and make
everything like
the first
he needs
to initiate
the new covenant
the agreement
between his
church
and himself
and his
students of heaven
to prepare
a place for us
one day
he will return
for a marriage
celebration
that will start
the rest of our
eternal lives
and write
relationships
with him
and worship
with every tribe
nation
and time
sounds magicically
what I mean
it's for us
an incredibly
powerful truth
but
and this is all
about real people
real life
right
this truth
exists
in peace
we live
between
the cup of sin
and the cup of celebration
we've been
offered salvation
forgiveness
abundant life
now yet
we look around
and we exist
in a world
filled with sin
suffering
injustice
and love
how do we
reconcile
these two things
Jesus keeps
telling us
that we
who are
suffering
in him
can begin
to live
towards
the kingdom
of God
we can
begin
to live
towards
worshiping
him
without a
whole heart
loving soul
and strength
and we can
begin
through the
power of
the Holy Spirit
to love
our neighbor
as ourselves
we can
begin
to create
a kingdom
oasis
where
the kingdom
of God
exists
not perfectly
but in parts
where a
light
shining
in the darkness
where there's a
city
on a hill
that demonstrates
God's kingdom
we can
live
towards
the kingdom
of God
and a
world
controlled
against
things
isn't
just some
cool story
from some
ancient
religious
press
with no
indications
on your
life
if Jesus
is who
John claims
he is
and if he
did
but John
claims as
he did
then everything
can be
there's
power
to see
forgiveness
and healing
and you're
better
there's
victory
over sin
and restoration
for your
play
there's
hope
and there's
for hurting
people
peace
that has
to
understanding
and joy
and then it's
because Jesus
drank your
cup out of
suffering
so you can
drink his
cup
by the way
I was
talking to
somebody
the other
day
I was
struggling
with
I was in
a dark
place
and I was
10 years ago
where it was
coming from
and it
turned out
that it
was all
beauty
and regret
shame
and guilt
and decisions
that they
made in the
place
really good
man
you never
stopped
stalking
because of
the things you
did
that screwed up
the life
that you're
now living
Jesus
out
with
forgiveness
is
healing
and restoration
and hope
you don't
have to
lose
in
shame
or guilt
you get
to walk
in freedom
in your
life
and that
doesn't
mean
that the
decisions
you made
in the
classroom
have
consequences
for today
but it
means
that you
get to
start
a new
life
walking
in
forgiveness
and doing
your best
to reconcile
the mistakes
that happened
in the past
I believe
as you
trust it
in Jesus
with your
sin and
suffering
do you
believe in
his future
resolution
are you
firmly
trusting him
with the
blessing
of your
life
I wrote
this miracle
and it's
rich
symbol
that's
really hard
to say
I should
remember
that when I
wrote it
down
it's
rich
symbolism
encourages
you
to
believe
or
strengthen
your
belief
of
who
Jesus
is
and what
he
said
because I
truly believe
that
trust him
in Jesus
and his
everything
Marianne
Thompson
says this
about the
signs of
John
she
says
indeed
there
are
really
one
of
two
responses
to
the
sign
belief
or
unbelief
one
even
accepts
the
testimony
of the
sign
that
reveals
Jesus
to be
the one
through
whom
that's
life giving
work
is accomplished
for one
is not
faith is not
the premise
for
but rather
the desired
response
to
Jesus
so my
final
question
for us
this morning
what's
your response
how do you
trust it
for Jesus
in his
settings
have you
trusted the
thing that
this
sign
makes the
claim of
that or
how do you
know
and look
I'm not
firing
brainstones
guilt
and
killing
people
like
I don't
believe
that it's
my job
to convince
you
that this
is
true
I just
get the
privilege
of
sharing
it
and my
prayer
is that
you would
examine
it for
yourself
and make
the decision
so I'm
going to
I'm not
saying
to do
something
wrong
I don't
know
what I've
ever done
as a
preacher
and then
I'm going
to ask
everybody
about it
you know
the old
school
guys
but what I
don't want
this to be
is I don't
want this
to be
some emotional
response
it says
you need to
play in the
box
that means
doing great
spirit and
remember
and what I
want to do
is I want to
get those of
you who have
never crossed
that 50.001%
line of
safe
for those of
you who have
been searching
and asking
and speaking
and reading
and praying
that 50.001%
and you
do
not
safe
and
anything
in this
text
persuading
you to
move from
whatever
percentage
you are
before
it's
over
50.1%
if you
want to
make a
decision
for the
first time
I want to
give you
an opportunity
to do
that he's
between
you
and you
and for
those of
you that
have already
made that
decision
and read
our
message
closer
as
you must
be praying
that the
spirit of
your work
and also
just thinking
about
how this
message
might encourage
you to
move from
50.001%
from whatever
percentage
you are
after to
the next
percentage
generally
that your
faith would
increase
that your
trust in
Jesus
would
increase
and when
your trust
increases
your obedience
so many
of us
that are
followers of
Jesus
and have
been following
Jesus
for a long
time
and we
think
our
faith grows
when we
show our
that is
more
than
I
know
more
about
Jesus
I
must
have
a
better
faith
a deeper
relationship
do you
know
more
about
Jesus
or do
you
know
Jesus
better
and are
you
following
him
more
so if
you want
to be
a people
who
grow
in
our
faith
it
shouldn't
just
be
information
but it
should
also
be
everything
else
all right
I
then
hold
down
every
eye
close
if you're
in here
and you've
never
placed
the faith
in Jesus
you've
never
crossed
the line
of
Jesus
the Lord
in my life
and you want to do it today
and you want to do it in this moment
you might do it in your car
on your way home
in bed tonight
you might do it a million other places
I'd still love to hear about it
but if you want to do that right
now
I'd ask you to just raise it in
I'm just
in here
thank you
John
Moses
that
we might
believe
in Jesus
the
anointed
one
the Messiah
from Israel
God
in the
flesh
that
we might
believe that
and through
believing that
we might receive
abundant
lifestyle
and eternal
life
in the future
let's pray
Father
we're so grateful
to Jesus
to drink
out of the suffering
so that we need to drink
things healthy
and may we stick
with that today
and understand
the temptations
for our lives
for those of us
struggling with
the famous past decisions
with the fear
of what's
coming next
in our life
would we need to
release that
to you
knowing
that you are
going
with
God
you're
coming
with
making
that you're
in control
and we do
a people
that don't
just take
advantage
of the grace
of God
I don't
also know
when I start
to fix
so we just
keep on saying
God
Jesus
do it for us
we just
help to
celebrate
so let's
just have
a good life
and we
shouldn't
just keep
on saying
we should
submit
dearly
to
obedience
to you
let that be
out of you
every day
so let's
stand like
amen